SYLVAIN LECLERCQ

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

***** +33 7 83 21 08 82

52 rue de Gavarnie 78180, Montigny-le-Bx

contact@sylvainleclercq.com

FRANCE

https://github.com/de-passage

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sylvain-leclercq-12b933154/

PROFILE

Detailed, interactive resume online at sylvainleclercq.com.

Self taught programmer with over 15 years of personal experience. I am highly autonomous and motivated, passionate about learning ever more about computer science and experimenting with new tools and technologies.

SKILLS

C++, Boost, Qt	Haskell	Javascript, Re	act, node.js, Vu	uejs, CoffeeScript
C#, .NET, WPF	HTML/CSS	PureScript	Elm	Ruby, Ruby on Rails
Python, Django	Lua	SQL (PostgreSQ	L), MondoDB	Git, Linux

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Nexter Systems

Mar. 2018 – Dec. 2019 Versailles, France

Development of a guidance and communication system for military armored vehicles. Responsibilities involved:

- Design and implementation of a custom database synchronization system (C++)
- Refactoring of a legacy code base to improve reliability and modularity (C#)
- Implementation of business-critical features in a large application (C#)
- Set up of unit testing frameworks and implementation of unit tests (C++ and C#)
- Profiling and performance improvements (C#)
- Implementation of tools to help development and quality analysis processes (C# and C++)
- Analysis and documentation of legacy code bases (C++ and C#)

Previous Experiences

From 2012 to 2018, I occupied several unqualified jobs. both part time and full-time, in France, Japan, South Korea, Taiwan and Australia. As they are largely irrelevant to my current situation, I only list them on my website.

All my public projects are available on my Github.

https://github.com/de-passage/conduit.purs

Front end for a Medium-like website, implemented in PureScript

https://github.com/de-passage/conduit-rocket.rust

Back end for a Medium-like website, implemented in Rust, backed by PostgreSQL.

https://github.com/de-passage/de-passage.github.io

Front end of my personal website, implemented in PureScript

https://github.com/de-passage/game-of-life.coffee

Conway's Game of life, implemented in CoffeeScript with React

https://github.com/de-passage/urlshortener-ms

https://github.com/de-passage/whoami-ms

https://github.com/de-passage/timestamp-ms

Very simple microservices implemented in CoffeeScript with node.js.

https://github.com/de-passage/front-end-games.elm

Small game collection implemented in Elm.

https://github.com/de-passage/basics.cpp

Some common data structures (lists, arrays, binary tree, hash table) and associated algorithms implemented in C++.

LANGUAGES

French English Japanese	Native Near bilingual Fluent		passed in 2013 with 990 pts LPT N1 passed in 2014
EDUCATION			
ESCEM 2010 – 2014	French Busines	ss school.	4 th and 5 th semesters completed at Meiji University, Japan
2008 – 2010	Two-year highly selective classes to prepare for the competitive exams to the French Business Schools		
2008	Baccalauréat		French national high-school leaving diploma